Again.
So here we will be talking about radio frequency power and signal interface.
So we'll be describing the communication between the type A and type B.
So here in fact we will be presenting the different type of modulations for either type A and type B.
Then we'll be talking also about the different techniques that describe this type of communication.
What are the modulation.
What are the bit rates.
What are the how is the communication from the reader to the cart or from the car to the reader?
So first of all, the basics of data transmission, as you can see here in this picture.
So on the left we have a polling device what we can call.
So call the reader.
And on the right you have the listening device or what we can call the card.
So in fact like the RFID 14 443 and Felica standards, NFC uses inductive coupling.
As with the transformer principle, the near magnetic field of two conductive coils is used to couple
the polling device, which is also the initiator, and the listening device, which is also the target.
The operating frequency is 1350 six megahertz, as we have seen earlier, and also the communication
is characterized by a bit rate of 106 kilobit per second, 212 kilobit per second, for 24 kilobit per
second, and eight 48 kilobit per second are used.
The modulation schemes are on off amplitude modulation with different modulation depth 100% or 10 or
10% and bpsk depending on the type of communication I mean by that depending if we are using a type
A communication or a type B communication.
So in fact, a variation in the impedance of the receiving device results in changes in the amplitude
or phase of the antenna voltage of the interrogation device.
This technique is called load modulation.
So the load modulation is the technique that characterizes the communication.
In fact it uses an an auxiliary carrier at eight 48kHz.
As you can see here earlier here in the picture on the left and also on the right which is baseband
modulated and varies the impedance of the receiving device.
So here in this table we can see the different options and the different parameters of type A and type
B communication.
So the ISO 14 443 standard defines two different communication interfaces which are designated type
A and type B.
The reason for standard standardizing two different protocols does not arise from technical considerations,
but instead from the fact that several technical concepts from various manufacturers already existed.
When the ISO 14,443 standard was being generated, as is unfortunately often the case with standardization.
The diverging interests of the involved parties prevented them from agreeing on a signal on a single
protocol.
Although this would have been more sensible in the interest of easy interoperability as a compromise
solution, agreement was reached on the two protocols mentioned above, and they were published as an
international standard in June 2001.
So car terminals must support both protocols in order to achieve full interoperability with all cars
compliant with ISO 14,443.
Since most cars support only one protocol.
When the terminal is on the idle state.
While waiting to detect a proximity card, it must periodically switch between the two communication
protocols.
So this enables it to recognize both type A and type B cards.
So in fact, this means that a card can support type A or type B.
A single card cannot support both types.
So that's why because we don't know what kind of reader we will communicate with.
By default, the reader should support both types A and B.
So by by doing that, the reader has to start the communication by sending in a loop.
The first type a command and the first type B command.
We will see that later in the digital part.
So when I say the first type A command and the type B command I'm talking about request A and the request
B.
This is like saying hello to the card.
So once the PCD has recognized a card, it continues to use the corresponding communication protocol
until the card is deactivated by the terminal or leaves the working range of the terminal.
Of course, it can happen that type A cards receives a type B command, or type B cards receives a type
A command during polling.
So polling means that we are going to send a request A and a request B in a loop until we get a card
and continue the communication with.
To prevent this from blocking communication, there is a rule for the card response.
In such situations, the basic rule is that the card must return to the idle state after receiving an
unmodulated signal for five milliseconds.
In fact, the standard describes examples of the card response to a known commands.
That's why now I'm going to present the different way of communication for both type A and B.
We will see in the next slides.
But here before we do that let's have a look on this table.
So as we have seen earlier, the power supply for type A and type B communications, which are described
through the ISO 14 443 standards, is characterized by a 1350 six megahertz inductive coupling.
So 1350 six megahertz is the frequency that describes or characterize the NFC communication.
Then we have the field strength.
So here we have 1.58A/m to 7.58 amp per meter.
To be honest with you, in fact, this is the most common range that we use in our daily activities
because 1.5A/m to 7.5A parameter is the range that characterizes the class one antenna.
I mean the class one size for the antennas.
And then when we go higher in the class class two, three, four, five and six, the range changes.
So then we have the PCD to pick communication for.
Type A is characterized by an SK 100%, which is done through a modified Miller coding.
So the a SK 100% means amplitude shift keying.
So we are going to reduce the amplitude until we reach almost zero.
So amplitude shift keying of 100%.
However, for a type B it's an ask of 10%.
And for the coding we're using we are using the NS coding.
So the other way from the pack to PCD communication, if we are in a 106 kilobit per second bit rate,
we are going to use the OC modulated and the Manchester for 212 to 8 48 kilobit per second.
We use Bpsk and Nzsl coding.
However, for type B from 106 to 848 we use Bpsk and Nzsl coding.
So there is a sentence that we always see when we talk about NFC communication, which is the carrier
frequency.
So the carrier frequency, which is symbolized by FC in the standard of an RFID system as defined in
the ISO 14,443, is 1350 six megahertz plus -seven kilohertz.
The carrier is used to supply power to the PC via a transformer coupling and the resulting induced voltage.
The modulation of the carrier signal allows the PCD to transmit information to the PC.
So here we will be talking about the principle of modulation type A versus type B.
So in fact cards may be type A and type B, both of which communicate via radio at 1350 six megahertz.
The main differences between these types concern modulation methods.
As you can see here on the left we have the modulation type.
For type A it's like 100% ask.
So as you see here, normally in the beginning the signal from the reader is like a perfect sinusoidal.
So it's something like this.
Then you see here when we apply the isq 100%, we decrease the signal until we reach almost zero.
So that's why we have the word ask 100%.
And then we have an overshoot.
And then it tries to go back to its initial value.
When we do this some time some timings will be generated like T1, t2, T3 and T4.
Okay.
So for example, T1 is the timing from the beginning of the falling edge until the beginning of the
rising edge.
So here for example here this part is the overshoot.
Here on the right we have the modulation for the type B.
It's an ask of 10%.
And for doing that we have some parameters that we will be generated like the parameter b and the timings
d f and tr f for falling r for rising.
So what about the modulation principle?
So the PCD uses an amplitude modulation of the carrier frequency to transmit information.
The modulation used is either type A or type B during communication from PCD to Pic.
Type A is used, providing 100% amplitude modulation.
And type B involves 10% amplitude shift keying in the communication from Pic to PCD.
As you have seen earlier, a distinction must be made between the individual bit rates.
Different modulation types are used depending on the bit rate, to detect whether a type A or type B
pic is present in the PCD operating field.
The PCD alternates the modulation.
It then selects the modulation matching the Pic type in order to initialize communication.
So here in the first part let's focus on the type A communication interface.
So during initialization and anti-collision a bitrate of 106 kilobit per second is used for data transmission
from the terminal to the card or from the reader to the card with type A cards.
After initialization and anti-collision, any of the following bitrates can be used for data transmission
106 kilobit per second, two, 12, 424, and eight 48 Kilobit per second.
So regarding the transmission from PCD to Pic, digital amplitude modulation one for for 100% of Assk
at a bit rate of 106kbps with modified Miller coding is using is used for data transmission from the
PCD to to the Pic.
So here on the left we have the picture that describes the modified Miller coding.
So as I said, the the digital amplitude modulation at a bit rate of 106 kilobit per second with modified
Miller coding is used for data transmission from the reader to the car, with a maximum pose of interval
of three microseconds.
This relatively short pose makes it easier to provide a continuous supply of power to the cart.
So coding of a bit sequence from the terminal to the cart using a type A communication with 100% ask
modified Miller coding and 106 kilobit per second.
It is described through this picture.
In fact, the coding is defined as follows.
So for the logic one.
Pose after half the bit interval for the logic zero no pose, with the following exceptions.
So a first one.
If there are two or more logic zero states in succession, there is a pose at the start of the bit interval.
Then, if the first bit of a protocol frame is zero, it's represented by a pose at the start of the
bit interval.
Then we have a start of message, which is a pose at the start of a bit interval end of message which
is logic zero, followed by one bit with no pose and then no data, which means no pose for the duration
of at least two bits.
Then, regarding the transmission from the car to the terminal, we use Manchester coding.
So load modulation for data transmission from the car to the reader, using a subcarrier with a frequency
of FC divided by 16, which means eight 48kHz uh kilobit per second, and Manchester coding with a bit
rate of 106 kilobit per second.
And okay, the figure shows the voltage on the card coil.
So the coding is defined as follows.
So logic one.
Here means that the carrier is modulated by the subcarrier in the first half of the bit interval, then
logic zero.
The carrier is modulated by the subcarrier in the second half of the bit interval.
So what about the type B communication interface?
So here, as you can see here we have an ask of 10%.
So ask modulation with a modulation index of 10% is used for the data transmission.
So a continuous supply of power is achieved by using a relatively low modulation index, defined such
that at least 8,686% of the carrier field is always available.
So that's why we are talking about a 10% of ask the bit rate during initialization, and anti-collision
is 106.
Any of the other bit rates can be used after initialization and interpolation, as I said earlier.
And we will talk about this more in the digital part, the the initialization of the communication from
the first command to the last command of the layer three of ISO 14 443.3 is always done at 106 kilobit
per second until we reach the PES.
When we talk about the protocol negotiation, bitrate negotiation, then after that we change the bit
rates if needed.
So regarding the transmission from PC to PC.
Coding of a bit sequence from the terminal to the card using a type B communication interface with 10%.
Ask is characterized by an energy coding and a bit rate of 106 kilobit per second, as we have seen
earlier.
Then regarding the transmission from the card to the terminal.
The communication is described or characterized by an r, z, L encoding, so load modulation with a
subcarrier is also used for data transmission from the card to the terminal with type B cards.
Here as well.
Same for type A, the subcarrier frequency FS is 848kHz.
In contrast to type A, the subcarrier is modulated using binary phase shift keying, Bpsk and Nrzi
coding with a bitrate of 106 kilobit per second.
During initialization and anti-collision.